Lenovo Linux Diagnostics - Bootable CD               
Software readme file
Version 4.7.0.8081


Overview
=========
Lenovo Linux Diagnostics - Bootable CD is a diagnostic tool that can be booted itself and tests hardware devices in Lenovo ThinkPad, ThinkCentre, ThinkStation, ThinkServer and IdeaPad.


SUPPORTED SYSTEMS
=================
* All Thinkpad
* All ThinkCentre
* All ThinkStation
* All IdeaCentre
* Lenovo EsSential V480s, V480, V480c, V580, V580c, V490u, B475e, B575e, B480, B490, B490s, B580, B590, M490, M490s, M495
* Lenovo EsSential V4400, V4400u, B4400, B4450s, B5400, M4400, M4400s, M4450,M5400 K2450, K4350, K4450, E4430
* Lenovo EsSential K29, K49, E49
* Lenovo EsSential G480, G485, G580, G400, G400s, G405, G405s, G410, G410s, G585, G500, G500s, G505, G505s, G510, G510s, G700, G710, G780


CHANGE HISTORY
==============
4.7.0.8081
ADD: Storage - NVMe
UPD: Storage - eMMC
ADD: Sensors (Windows)

FIX: CLI - The eMMC test is hangs the app on Extended tests
FIX: eMMC - Write test returning Warning status
FIX: Storage - The storage module is displaying duplicated device
FIX: Storage - The application is displaying 3 hard disks in Windows, but in Linux Bootable only one hard disk
FIX: Storage - The app is tripling the informations of USB Storage device

4.6.0.7960
ADD: Services Group - Audio (Windows)
ADD: Services Group - Wired (Windows)
ADD: Export Test Log to PDF (Windows)

4.5.0.7875	
UPD: Motherboard - Chipset Test
UPD: Motherboard - USB Test

FIX: VideoCard - The message appears incomplete on LSC Cli
FIX: Display Interface - The field "Monitor Name" is duplicated at System Information
FIX: Keyboard Bootable - The keyboard module is showing in the bootable.
FIX: Keyboard-The canceled status of the PS2 Test is not aligned whith status of the USB keyboard Test
FIX: Keyboard - The PS/2 test cancels the execution when the user confirms the pop-up message by pressing Enter button
FIX: Video Card - Some video card tests are not canceled when the event Switch User happens
FIX: Display Interface - EDID checksum test is not show on LSC Cli when the user forces the "Switch user" event
FIX: The system show Passed status when the test is canceled
FIX: The home screen size is not adjusted
FIX: Custon Template - By using French idiom and DPI with 200%, the description of the button is being cut.

4.4.0.7605:
ADD: Display Interface
ADD: Keyboard

UPD: Video Card - Reintroduce the parameters in the new test for AMD devices
UPD: Storage - Update tests names
UPD: Motherboard/FAN/Keyboard - Improvement on LDiagIO loading and access
UPD: Motherboard/USB - Improvement on Write Test on Linux
UPD: All Modules - Improve the cancel and system event verification on the modules - Part 1
	
FIX: eMMC - Lite is crashing during eMMC Write Test
FIX: LSC Lite - The home screen size is not correct when the user minimizes and restores the app
FIX: LSC Lite - By using French idiom, the progress bar is being cut
FIX: Custom Template - The application shows the symbol "%" in the message when a módule is not suported
FIX: Log history - The module's name is being displayed with characters cut
FIX: LSC Cli - Run all - The extended tests appear different from LSC Lite when I run all extended tests
FIX: LSC CLI - Storage - eMMC Storage Device Read Test do not test the specified disk regions
FIX: Lite bootable 4.1.0 , 4.0.0 X1 Carbon, keyboard keys problem
FIX: Video Card - The Extended Video Memory test is returning Failed status

4.3.0.7318
FIX: SMART Short Self Test timesout with Warning D30 and T540P


Supported Linux OS
--------------------
All operating system - Self Bootable

Supported Languages
-------------------
Lenovo Linux Diagnostics - Bootable CD provides a user interface in the 
following languages:

- English
- Portuguese
- German
- French
- Italian
- Spanish
- Dutch


DOWNLOADING THE INSTALLATION FILE
=================================
1. Click the file links to download the files from the Web page.
2. When prompted, select a drive and directory in which to save the
   downloaded files.


INSTALLATION
============
1. Burn the ISO to a CD using a media tool
2. Boot your computer with the CD or DVD you just created


LIMITATIONS AND CONSIDERATIONS
==============================
Limitations: 

*SATA Controller Mode needs to be set to AHCI in system BIOS if the system doesn't use UEFI BIOS


OPEN SOURCE CODE
================
For any open source code used in genearting this application, you can download it at
http://support.lenovo.com/us/en/lenovodiagnosticsolutions/tools/opensource


NOTICES
=======
LENOVO GROUP LTD. PROVIDES THIS PUBLICATION AS IS WITHOUT WARRANTY 
OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, 
THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS 
FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. Some jurisdictions do not allow disclaimer of 
express or implied warranties in certain transactions, therefore, this 
statement may not apply to you. This information could include technical 
inaccuracies or typographical errors. Changes are periodically made to 
the information herein; these changes will be incorporated in new editions 
of the publication. Lenovo may make improvements and/or changes in the 
product(s) and/or the program(s) described in this publication at any time 
without notice.


TRADEMARKS AND SERVICE MARKS
============================
The following terms are trademarks of Lenovo in the United States, other 
countries, or both: 

Lenovo
ThinkCentre
ThinkPad
ThinkServer
ThinkStation
IdeaPad
IdeaCentre

(C) Portions Copyright Lenovo 2005-2016.  All Rights Reserved.
(C) Portions Copyright FIT 2011-2016.  All Rights Reserved.

Microsoft, Windows and Windows Vista are trademarks of Microsoft Corporation in the United State and/or other countries.

Note to U.S. Government Users Restricted Rights -- Use,
duplication, or disclosure restricted by GSA ADP Schedule Contract
with Lenovo
